Marcel Breuer Papers
Marcel Breuer Papers
- Project records
  - UNIDENTIFIED
    - Published material
      - Raum I (circa 1930), tear sheet, pgs. 13-16; publication unknown; in German (Box 139, Folder 12)
Leiser Stores Leiser Stores
Levi Apartment Apartment for a Gymnastics Teacher
Levy House Levy House
Levy House, Addition Levy House, Addition
Levy Interior Levy Interior
Lewin House Lewin House
Litchfield High School Litchfield High School
London Building Exhibition, 1936 Garden City of the Future, Model
London Theater Studio London Theater Studio
Long Beach Hospital, Nurses' Residence Long Beach Hospital, Nurses' Residence
Maas House Maas House
Madison Park High School Campus High School
Madison Park Urban Renewal Madison Park Urban Renewal
Marcel Breuer House at Pocantico House in the Museum Garden, Museum of Modern Art
Marcel Breuer Tower Cleveland Trust Company, Headquarters
Marlborough Gallery Marlborough Gallery
Marshad House Marshad House
Martine House Martine House
Mary College University of Mary, Annunciation Priory of the Sisters of St. Benedict
Masters' houses (Bauhaus) Bauhaus Masters' Houses Interiors (Dessau)
McComb House McComb House
McGinnis House McGinnis House
McGinnis Penthouse Apartment (NSIBP) McGinnis Penthouse Apartment (NSIBP)
McMullen Beach House McMullen Beach House
Meiser Charette School Greenwich Village Public School 3
Meister Hall New York University Technology II
Melder House Haus M (Melder House)
Merck, Sharp and Dohme Merck, Sharp and Dohme
Miami House Binuclear House
Mills House Mills House
Mills House, Addition Mills House, Addition
Model Bathroom Model Bathroom
Moholy-Nagy Apartment Bauhaus Masters' Houses Interiors (Dessau)
Moholy-Nagy House Bauhaus Masters' Houses Interiors (Dessau)
MoMA house House in the Museum Garden, Museum of Modern Art
MoMA Intl.Competition for Low-Cost Furniture International Competition for Low Cost Furniture Design
Motley's Fashion Studio Motley's Fashion Studio
MSD Merck, Sharp and Dohme
Muche House Bauhaus Masters' Houses Interiors (Dessau)
Mundipharma, Headquarters and Manufacturing Plant Mundipharma, Headquarters and Manufacturing Plant
Museum for the Nordrhein-Westfalen Collection, Competition Museum for the Nordrhein-Westfalen Collection, Competition
Museum house House in the Museum Garden, Museum of Modern Art
Nassau State School State School for the Mentally Retarded
Near East Side Urban Development Project Bristol Center (Harrison State Development Corporation) Office Building
Neumann House Neumann House
Neumann House, Pool house Neumann House, Pool house
New Campus High School Campus High School
New England Merchants' Bank Building, Competition New England Merchants' Bank Building, Competition
New Haven Railroad, Locomotives and Passenger Cars New Haven Railroad, Locomotives and Passenger Cars
New Haven Railroad, Passenger Station (New London, CT) New Haven Railroad, Passenger Station (New London, CT)
New Haven Railroad, Passenger Station (Rye, NY) New Haven Railroad, Passenger Station (Rye, NY)
New Jersey Housing Project Duplex-Apartment Complex
New Kensington Project Aluminum City Terrace
New London Station New Haven Railroad, Passenger Station (New London, CT)
New York Apartment House Apartment House, New York
New York University Building Complex New York University Building Complex
New York University Residence Hall New York University Residence Hall
New York University Student Center New York University Student Center
New York University Technology I New York University Technology I
New York University Technology II New York University Technology II
New York World's Fair Exhibition Pennsylvania State Exhibition, World's Fair
North Station Industrial Building (NSIBP) McGinnis Penthouse Apartment (NSIBP)
Northfield Elementary School Northfield Elementary School
Nurses' Residence Long Beach Hospital, Nurses' Residence
O.E. McIntyre, Inc. O.E. McIntyre, Inc.
Oglala Community High School (Pine Ridge High School) Oglala Community High School (Pine Ridge High School)
Olgiata Parish Church (Chiesa parocchiale delle Sante Rufina e Seconda, Olgiata Romana) Olgiata Parish Church (Chiesa parocchiale delle Sante Rufina e Seconda, Olgiata Romana)
One Charles Center One Charles Center
Pack House Pack House
Pack House Addition Pack House Addition
Paepcke Vacation House Paepcke Vacation House
Paris Exhibition, 1930 Paris Werkbund Exhibition
Paris Werkbund Exhibition Paris Werkbund Exhibition
Park Avenue Tower 175 Park Avenue
Peabody Museum Peabody Museum
Pencil Points/Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company House, Competition Pencil Points/Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company House, Competition
Pennsylvania State Exhibition, World's Fair Pennsylvania State Exhibition, World's Fair
Peter Engel Science Center Saint John's Science Building
Philip Morris Manufacturing Facility Philip Morris Manufacturing Facility
Picker House Picker House
Pine Ridge High School Oglala Community High School (Pine Ridge High School)
Pirelli Tire Building Armstrong Rubber Company, Headquarters
Piscator Apartment Piscator Apartment
Pittsburgh Glass House Pencil Points/Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company House, Competition
Plas-2-Point House Plas-2-Point House
Polowczyk Hall New York University Technology I
Post-War House California Arts and Architecture/Pepperell Manufacturing Company House, Competition
Postwar House for Ladies' Home Journal Postwar House for Ladies' Home Journal
Potsdamer Platz Potsdamer Platz
Potter House Potter House
Princeton Institute Institute for Advanced Study, Members' Housing
Princeton Library Institute for Advanced Study, Library
Project for a Cathedral (St. Paul's) Project for a Cathedral (St. Paul's)
Purchase Hills Country Club of Purchase
Rand House Rand House
Realistic House in Georgia: Competition Sponsored by Progressive Architecture/Rich's Department Store Realistic House in Georgia: Competition Sponsored by Progressive Architecture/Rich's Department Store
Recreational Apartments Recreational Apartments
Reidemeister Apartment Reidemeister Apartment
Resort Town (Amenagement de la Cote Aquitaine) Resort Town (Amenagement de la Cote Aquitaine)
Rhoads Hall Bryn Mawr College Dormitory
Robeck House Breuer House II
Robert C. Weaver Federal Building Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Headquarters
Robinson (George) House Robinson (George) House
Robinson Hall Harvard University, Biology and Chemistry Building
Robinson House Robinson House
Rockefeller (Winthrop) House, Addition Rockefeller (Winthrop) House, Addition
Rockville Centre House Rockville Centre House
Roof Coping Project Roof Coping Project
Rose House Rose House
Rosen House Rosen House
Ross House Ross House
Roxbury Campus High School Campus High School
Royal Agricultural Show Gane's Pavilion
Rye Station New Haven Railroad, Passenger Station (Rye, NY)
S. Residence Binuclear House
Sackler II Mundipharma, Headquarters and Manufacturing Plant
Saier House Saier House
Saint Bernard Hall Saint John's Residence Hall II
Saint Boniface Hall Saint John's Residence Hall II
Saint John's Abbey and University Complex Saint John's Abbey and University Complex
Saint John's Campus Center (Student Union and Swimming Pavilion) Saint John's Campus Center (Student Union and Swimming Pavilion)
Saint John's Church and Campanile Saint John's Church and Campanile
Saint John's Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Bush Center Saint John's Hill Monastic Manuscript Library, Bush Center
Saint John's Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research Saint John's Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research
Saint John's Library Saint John's Library
Saint John's Monastery Wing Saint John's Monastery Wing
Saint John's Residence Hall I Saint John's Residence Hall I
Saint John's Residence Hall II Saint John's Residence Hall II
Saint John's Science Building Saint John's Science Building
Saint John's University Saint John's Abbey and University Complex
Saint Patrick Hall Saint John's Residence Hall II
Saint Thomas Aquinas Hall Saint John's Residence Hall I
Sandor House Sandor House
Sarah Lawrence College, Art Center Sarah Lawrence College, Art Center
Sarget-Ambrine, Headquarters and Pharmaceutical Laboratories Sarget-Ambrine, Headquarters and Pharmaceutical Laboratories
Sarget-Ambrine, Headquarters and Pharmaceutical Laboratories, Expansion (Sarget II) Sarget-Ambrine, Headquarters and Pharmaceutical Laboratories, Expansion (Sarget II)
Scarlet (tapestry) Tapestry Designs
Scarves by Vera, Showroom, 112 W. 9th Street, Los Angeles, CA Scarves by Vera, Showroom, 112 W. 9th Street, Los Angeles, CA
Scarves by Vera, Showroom, 1411 Broadway, 29th floor, New York, NY Scarves by Vera, Showroom, 1411 Broadway, 29th floor, New York, NY
Scarves by Vera, Showroom, 417 5th Avenue, 5th floor Scarves by Vera, Showroom, 417 5th Avenue, 5th floor
Scarves by Vera, Warehouse Scarves by Vera, Warehouse
Schmidt Apartment Schmidt Apartment
Schmitt Cottage Schmitt Cottage
Schneider House Schneider House
Scott House Scott House
Scott House, Addition Scott House, Addition
SEC (Secondary Education Complex) Campus High School
Seventy Square Meter Apartment Seventy Square Meter Apartment
Shangri-La Rose House
Shatsow House Coston House
Shuster Hall Hunter College Library, Classroom and Administration Buildings
Silver Hall New York University Residence Hall
Singer Apartment Singer Apartment
Sixty State Street Sixty State Street
Sliding Window Sliding Window
Small Metal House (Kleinmetallhaus), 1925-1926 Type Small Metal House (Kleinmetallhaus), 1925-1926 Type
Smith College, Dormitories, Competition Smith College, Dormitories, Competition
Smith House Smith House
Snower House Snower House
Sonnen-Turm Sun Tower
Soriano House Soriano House
South Boston Redevelopment Plan South Boston Redevelopment Plan
South Portal Building Department of Health, Education and Welfare (HEW), Headquarters (Hubert H. Humphrey Federal Building)
Southern New England Telephone Company, Traffic Service Position Systems Building Southern New England Telephone Company, Traffic Service Position Systems Building
Space Sculpture Space Sculpture
Spandau-Haselhorst Apartments Apartment-House Complex, Competition, Spandau-Haselhorst
Sports Complex Sports Complex
Spring Trade Fair, Competition Spring Trade Fair, Competition
St. Francis de Sales Church Church and Rectory of St. Francis de Sales
St. Paul's Cathedral, Competition Project for a Cathedral (St. Paul's)
Staehelin House Staehelin House
Starkey House (Alworth House) Starkey House (Alworth House)
State School for the Mentally Retarded State School for the Mentally Retarded
State University of New York at Buffalo, Faculty of Engineering and Applied Science Building Complex State University of New York at Buffalo, Faculty of Engineering and Applied Science Building Complex
Stillman (Edgar, Jr.) Cottage Stillman (Edgar, Jr.) Cottage
Stillman House I Stillman House I
Stillman House II Stillman House II
Stillman House III Stillman House III
Strobel Interior Strobel Interior
Strom Thurmond Federal Building and U.S. Courthouse Strom Thurmond Federal Building and U.S. Courthouse
Study for a 'binuclear house' California Arts and Architecture/Pepperell Manufacturing Company House, Competition
Stuyvesant Six: A Redevelopment Proposal Stuyvesant Six: A Redevelopment Proposal
Summer House Breuer Cottage
Summer House Addition Breuer Cottage, First Addition
Sun Tower Sun Tower
SUNY Buffalo State University of New York at Buffalo, Faculty of Engineering and Applied Science Building Complex
Sutton Place Apartment House, New York
Tanaguarena Apartments Recreational Apartments
Tandem Tennis Courts and Club Tandem Tennis Courts and Club
Tapestry Designs Tapestry Designs
Thompson House Thompson House
Thost House Thost House
Tibby House Tibby House
Tile Council of America Bathroom Model Bathroom
Tilley House Tilley House
Tomkins House Tomkins House
Torin Corporation (Nivelles) Torin Corporation (Nivelles)
Torin Corporation (Oakville) Torin Corporation (Oakville)
Torin Corporation (Penrith) Torin Corporation (Penrith)
Torin Corporation (Rochester, Indiana) Torin Corporation (Rochester, Indiana)
Torin Corporation (Swindon) Torin Corporation (Swindon)
Torin Corporation (Van Nuys) Torin Corporation (Van Nuys)
Torin Corporation, Administration Building Torin Corporation, Administration Building
Torin Corporation, Assembly Plant (Lawton) Torin Corporation, Assembly Plant (Lawton)
Torin Corporation, Franklin Drive Plant Torin Corporation, Franklin Drive Plant
Torin Corporation, Machine Division Factory Torin Corporation, Machine Division Factory
Torin Corporation, Technical Centers Torin Corporation, Technical Centers
Torrington High School Torrington High School
Torrington Manufacturing Co. Torin Corporation
Torrington UKD Torin Corporation (Swindon)
T-REX Corporate Center IBM Administrative, Laboratory and Manufacturing Facility, Phase I, II and III
Two Dressers for Mr. and Mrs. H. Beckhard Two Dressers for Mr. and Mrs. H. Beckhard
Ukranian State Theater, Competition Ukranian State Theater, Competition
UNESCO, Headquarters (Place de Fontenoy) UNESCO, Headquarters (Place de Fontenoy)
UNESCO, Headquarters (Porte Maillot) UNESCO, Headquarters (Porte Maillot)
UNESCO, Headquarters, 4th Building UNESCO, Headquarters, 4th Building
United States Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) headquarters building Department of Health, Education and Welfare (HEW), Headquarters (Hubert H. Humphrey Federal Building)
United States Embassy, The Hague United States Embassy, The Hague
University of Mary, Annunciation Priory of the Sisters of St. Benedict University of Mary, Annunciation Priory of the Sisters of St. Benedict
University of Massachusetts, Murray Lincoln Campus Center University of Massachusetts, Murray Lincoln Campus Center
University of Virginia, Physics Building University of Virginia, Physics Building
Ustinov House Ustinov House
Van der Wal House Van der Wal House
Van Leer Office Building Van Leer Office Building
Vassar College, Ferry Cooperative Dormitory (Ferry House) Vassar College, Ferry Cooperative Dormitory (Ferry House)
Ventris Apartment Ventris Apartment
Vine Cottage Schmitt Cottage
Visitor Arrival Center (VAC) Grand Coulee Dam, Columbia Basin Project, Visitor Arrival Center
Von der Heydt Apartment Heydt Apartment
Waldenmark Fischer House and Studio
Wannsee Golf House Office Wannsee Golf House Office
War Memorial (Cambridge Honor Roll) War Memorial (Cambridge Honor Roll)
Wayland Cottage Chamberlain Cottage
Weekend House, Types I and II Weekend House, Types I and II
Weintraub Agency Weintraub Agency
Weissenhof Housing Exhibition Weissenhof Housing Exhibition
Weissenhofsiedlung Weissenhof Housing Exhibition
Wellfleet Cottages Breuer Cottage Kepes Cottage Stillman (Edgar, Jr.) Cottage Wise House
West Queens High School West Queens High School
Westchester Reform Temple Westchester Reform Temple
Wethersfield Project Defense Housing
Wheaton College, Art Center, Competition Wheaton College, Art Center, Competition
Whitby School Whitby School
Whitney Museum of American Art Whitney Museum of American Art
Wilensky Apartment Wilensky Apartment
Winter Sports Hotel Hans Falkner Ski Lodge
Wise House Wise House
Wise House, Addition Wise House, Addition
Witalis House Witalis House
Wochenendhaus Weekend House, Types I and II
Wohn Hotel Apartment Hotel
Wohnbedarf Stores Wohnbedarf Stores
Wohnhaus I and II Dwelling (Wohnhaus) I and II
Wohnung eine gymnastik lehrerin Apartment for a Gymnastics Teacher
Wolfson Trailer House Wolfson Trailer House
Woods End colony Breuer House I Gropius House (Lincoln) Ford House
Yale University, Becton Engineering and Applied Science Center Yale University, Becton Engineering and Applied Science Center
Yankee Portables Yankee Portables
Young Master Houses BAMBOS Houses, Types 1, 2 and 3
Zagreb Hospital Jewish Hospital for 220 Beds, Competition
ZUP de Bayonne ZUP de Bayonne
1200 Square Feet House Postwar House for Ladies' Home Journal
175 Park Avenue 175 Park Avenue
1939 World's Fair Exhibition Pennsylvania State Exhibition, World's Fair
30 Beekman Place, 9th floor 30 Beekman Place, 9th floor